Rachel Ewaniuk

1144 State Road, Coopersburg PA 18036 |ewaniukrn09@hotmail.com *Cell:* (484) 707-3396, *Home:* (610) 346-6651

OBJECTIVE

To obtain employment as a music educator in an environment where I have the ability to help students reach their full potential.

SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATIONS

Ambitious *Cum Laude* graduate of Mansfield University with a double major in Music Education and Music Industry with a concentration in Technology. Knowledge and experience in the following areas:

Teaching, Music-All instruments with a concentration in brass, Marching Ensembles, Audio Recording, Audio Editing, Live Sound, Music Notation Software, ProTools editing software.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Music: Music Education ~ Cum Laude

Bachelor of Music: Music Industry with a concentration in Technology ~ Cum Laude

August 2007 – May 2011

Mansfield University | Mansfield, PA

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

Private Lesson Teacher

July 2012 – Present

The Lesson Center | Trexlertown & Coopersburg, PA

• Responsible for giving private instrumental lessons to beginner students.

Private Lesson Teacher

August 2012 – Present

Saucon Valley Music | Hellertown, PA

• Responsible for giving private instrumental lessons to beginner students.

Middle School General Music Teacher

January 2014 – June 2014

Harrison-Morton and South Mountain Middle Schools | Allentown, PA

- General music Grades 6-8
- Responsible for creating and teaching lesson plans for the middle school general music classroom

Elementary General Music Teacher

August 2011 – June 2012

Owatin Creek Elementary School | Reading, PA

- General Music Grades K-4
- Responsible for creating and teaching lesson plans for the elementary general music classroom.

Marching Band Assistant

Fall 2011, 2012

Palisades High School Marching Band

- Volunteered time to help run music rehearsals
- Assisted students in learning drill and music

Substitute Teacher

August 2012 – January 2014

Palisades School District, Pennridge School District, Saucon Valley School District

• Day to Day substitute teacher, music specialty

Student Teacher

March 14, 2011 – May 5, 2011

Addison Junior/Senior High School | Addison, NY

- Instrumental Music Lessons grades 7-12, Instrumental rehearsals.
- Responsible for teaching individual instrumental music lessons for grades 7 -12. In charge of rehearing the 7th grade band, 8th grade band and senior high wind ensemble during class time.

Student Teacher

January 19, 2011 – March 8, 2011

Westfield Elementary School | Westfield, PA

- General Music grades K 6, Instrumental Music Lessons grade 4-6, Beginner Band Rehearsals
- Responsible for creating and teaching lesson plans for the general music classroom, grades K 6. Taught private instrumental music lessons for grades 4 6. Responsible for rehearing the Beginner Band

Private Instructor

Fall 2008 – May 2011

University Chapter of NAfME Lesson Program

• Taught beginner brass lessons to local students.

Youth Music Camp Counselor

July 2008 and July 2009

Mansfield University Youth Music Camp Ages 10 - 14

- Camp Counselor in charge of 8 students
- Assisted in teaching the various music classes offered

WORK EXPERIENCE

Sound Engineer

May 2010 - present

Sonlight Productions LLC | Quakertown, PA

- Worked with audio recording, post production and live sound venues.
- Hired part time upon completion of an internship. Assist the owner in recording clients, working with editing the recorded audio as well as going out on live sound jobs and setting up, running and disassembling the audio equipment.
- Ran sound for a benefit put on by Dave Ivory, the president of the Philadelphia Chapter of the Grammy's.

Sound Engineer

August 2009-May 2011

Mansfield University Jazz Ensemble | Mansfield, PA

• In charge of setting up, running and disassembling audio equipment for jazz ensemble performances.

Swing Shift Manager

August 2004 – May 2011

McDonald's Restaurant 6219 | Hellertown, PA

- Responsible for efficiently running a shift as well as dealing with customer service.
- Entrusted with opening and closing responsibilities, supervising at least ten crew members, provide excellent customer service, and resolve customer issues.

PROFESSIONAL MEMBERSHIPS / AFFILIATIONS

- National Association for Music Educators (NAfME)
- Pennsylvania Music Educators Association (PMEA)
- Sigma Alpha Iota ~ International Music Fraternity
- Bushwackers Drum and Bugle Corps Rookie of the Year Award 2012